MWANGI JESSE MBARIA

P.O. Box 3917-01000, Thika. Mobile: +254703-705137/ +254774-293016

Email: jessebaryah@gmail.com

Personal profile statement.

A disciplined, Adaptable and motivated leather science and technology graduate, intending to continue my development as a leather technologist. I think in terms of results and objectives. I am enthusiastic, and I work with decisiveness and conviction. I have a proactive attitude and find positive ways to stimulate and engage with people.

Core skills and Achievements.

Research project to determine the nutritional value of the tannery green fleshing for potential use in Aqua feeds formulation thus reduction of tannery solid waste. Hence replacement of fish meal with proteinaceous tannery solid waste will be the best approach to ease out solid waste disposal problem for environmentalist and also beneficial as an economic feed in aquaculture.

- Microsoft office packages.
- Excellent communication skills & teamwork.

WORK EXPERIENCE

2021- to date; Personal Development & Engagements Transcribing.

- I mustered improved turnaround time whereby transcripts can really speed up a video editors' workflow.
- I also acquired an improved audience comprehension.
- Engaging in small-scale businesses/personal development in food, groceries & beverages.

May- July 2019 Industrial Attachment

Leather Industries of Kenya

- I acquired excellent designing skills combined with mental ability and artistic finesse.
- I ensured that a proper research and quality control is at its place when testing and analysis is done in the lab and for that chemical, dye stuffs and small-scale apparatus are used.
- I acquired the knowledge of maintaining stringent quality control of the leather products throughout the process, from wet blue to crust to finished leather and all aspect of production entirely undertaken in-house.

December 2013-January 2014 Kiambu County.

Data analyst

- I participated in carrying out data entry for Baseline survey for farmers in Kiambu County whereby I was able to analyze the current situation of farmers' Association and cooperation in the Rural pilot villages to strengthen the functions and roles of farmers' cooperatives and association in the Disaster Risk Management.
- I acquired the basic technical concepts and data and their relevance to food assistance programmes to farmers with a focus on rural livelihood programming linkages to markets and strengthening their cooperatives and association.

Education.

MAY 2023 (Ongoing) Estimated Completion Date (NOVEMBER 2023)	African Centre for Data science & Analytics (AfriCDSA)	Certified Data Scientist.
2016-2020	University of Nairobi	BSc Leather Science and Technology Quality assurance, Chemical Engineering, Tannery Engineering, Leather science, Analytical techniques, Leather technology
2012- 2015	Thika High School	Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education (KCSE)

Memberships & Leadership positions

Current member of the Kenya Association of Leather Technologist & Scientists (KALTS).

Class representative - Leather Science & Technology class of 2020.

Official - Nairobi University Leather Student Association (NULSA) from 2016 to 2017.

Hobbies and Interest

I enjoy reading non-fictious books,

Learning new languages,

Socializing with friends and family.

REFERENCES

Mr. Joel Mwondu

Course coordinator (University of Nairobi)

Leather science and technology

Tel: +254717186315

Email: Joelmwondu@uonbi.ac.ke

Mr. Dennis Kimaiga

Secretary

The Kenya Association of Leather Technologist and Scientist (KALTS)

Tel: +254715431073

Email: dkimaiga@uonbi.ac.ke